# **E.J.** Sahala (they/them)

SF Bay Area, or Remote

**J** +1.408.218.2006

cv@saha.la

in https://www.linkedin/in/ejsdotsh

• https://github.com/ejsdotsh

★ https://ejs.sh

I am a network architect and reliability engineer with 24 years of experience specializing in the architecture, design, implementation, and operation of secure, large-scale backbone, data center, cloud, and enterprise networks, and in developing effective, empathetic, inclusive, and sustainable engineering teams and cultures.

I have a passion for solving infrastructure challenges programmatically through software, and want to use human-first design principles to guide the research, development, and innovative application of modern technology to create collaborative solutions to network operations, reliability, and scaling problems.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Senior Cloud Network Reliability Engineer

**Adobe** - 9/2021-12/2022

- Technical lead for the global corporate network team to engineer automation solutions for wired and wireless enterprise, data center, and WAN (AS1313) implementation, security, reliability, and operation
- Championed initiatives to add rigor to network engineering practices including design and operations reviews, blameless post-mortems, sustainable on-call, and automating configuration and operation

# **Senior Network Engineer**

**Box** - 11/2019-8/2021

- Improved the performance, capacity, and reliability of Box's global WAN, data center, peering (AS33011), and multi-cloud infrastructure, as well as leading cross-team initiatives to increase operational efficiency and velocity
- Enabled executive visibility of cross-team projects and network status by creating and maintaining dashboards and documentation in Confluence, Jira, and Splunk
- Partnered with NRE and SRE to overhaul monitoring and observability with Sensu, PagerDuty, LibreNMS, Splunk, simplifying alert configuration and significantly improving alert utility/signal-to-noise ratio

#### **Principal Network Engineer**

**HERE Technologies** - 8/2018-10/2019

- Design, automation, reliability, performance, and scaling of HERE's global on-premise (AS1248) and cloud network infrastructure enabling specialized mapping technologies, location data, and automotive navigation services
- Identified software bugs and rewrote QoS policies to resolve multiple long-standing trouble tickets, reduced packet loss and improved throughput 5-10x globally
- Edge network redesign; hybrid multi-cloud interconnection and inter-VPC/VPN routing, virtualized edge compute/network services (FW, LB, DNS, HTTP/HTTPS, VPN), 100G migration roadmap

# **Senior Network Engineer**

**Gaikai/Sony** - 1/2017-5/2018

- Network planning, design, implementation, and operation of global WAN, edge peering (AS33353), and data centers for PlayStation Now's game streaming services
- Developed and implemented documentation, process, and training improvements which increased operational efficiency and reduced deployment times by 10%
- Designed and implemented routing and load-balancing changes reducing intra-regional latency 2-4ms

last updated: 2023/08/19 1 of 3 cv@saha.la | +1.408.218.2006

# Senior Engineer - Network Strategy & Planning

Microsoft - 3/2014-1/2017

- Led company-wide initiatives to enhance customer experience, improve network performance and reliability, and optimize the existing peering (AS8075), CDN, and backbone infrastructure
- Collaborated with O365 and Field Services to increase customer retention and satisfaction; created and presented training and documentation, streamlined service activation and escalation processes
- Education, outreach, and strategic partnership building at events and conferences (NANOG, RIPE, PTC, GPF); elected to DE-CIX Customer Advisory Board
- Developed capacity management tooling unblocking 60+ site builds and saving \$15-million in CAPEX

# Systems (Sales) Engineer

**Juniper Networks** - 5/2012-8/2013

- Involved with all aspects of pre-/post-sales to a global service provider; developed consultative relationships with technical and executive decision makers, led architecture and design reviews
- Key team contributor in transforming resistance into success to exceed quota, and deliver over \$40million in sales revenue

# **Network Architect/Staff Engineer**

**Infocrossing/Wipro** - 7/2010-5/2012

- Definition, development, and implementation of backbone (AS19229), cloud, and data center networks and solution designs for a managed services provider (MSP)
- IP Manager, developed training and implemented process, procured v4 & v6 addresses from RIRs

# **Principal IP Engineer**

Intelepeer - 3/2009-6/2010

Hired to stabilize, redesign, and rebuild the network of a wholesale VoIP carrier (AS32385); led
equipment installs, site builds, and successfully completed migrations improving network availability
from <95% to 99.99%, reducing OPEX by 30%, and increasing capacity 2000%</li>

# **Tech Lead - Senior Network Engineer**

Yahoo! - 5/2007-2/2009

- Co-led the global teams responsible for Yahoo's edge (AS10310), backbone, and data center networks; worked with peers and providers to implement and troubleshoot connectivity worldwide
- Collaborated with Architecture to develop and document detailed network designs and new technology migration plans; implemented those plans with zero service interruption

#### **Principal Engineer**

**Alcatel-Lucent NZ** - 8/2006-5/2007

• Lead Architect on complex solution design projects for New Zealand's largest network and telecomm provider; contributed to ongoing metro and backbone redesign projects

## **Lead IP Network Engineer**

tw telecom - 6/2005-7/2006

- Team lead responsible for lifecycle and vendor management, network implementation and operation (AS4323), and was final escalation for all IP/MPLS/telephony-related products and services
- Installed and configured stop-gap monitoring tools, lowering MTTR and beating the commercial solution by two-years; implemented Cfengine to automate administration of Debian, RHEL, and Solaris

#### **Lead Network Engineer**

**Terremark** - 1/2004-1/2005

Responsible for performance, design, implementation, and configuration of a multi-national, carrier-neutral IXP and data center provider; performed traffic/flow analysis in support of peering (AS23148) activities; mentored junior engineers

# **Senior IP Engineer**

Fusiontel - 9/2002-1/2004

- Sole network engineer; responsible for design, documentation, and 24/7 operation, implemented L2VPN with AToM, configured and maintained routing (AS16525), SIP/H.323 gateways; managed IP addressing, administered Solaris & Debian servers providing DHCP, NTP, HTTP, and DNS
- Authored and presented comprehensive company-wide training; reduced escalations, lowered MTTR, and increased sales closure rate

last updated: 2023/08/19 2 of 3 cv@saha.la | +1.408.218.2006

Network Engineer USA.net - 3/2001-5/2002

• Cabled, installed, configured, and maintained LAN, WAN, and data center routers (AS14454), switches, firewalls, load balancers, and VPN concentrators; managed IP addressing, NTP, and DNS

NOC Technician Various - 9/1999-1/2001

#### **Lance Corporal**

**U.S. Marine Corps Reserve** - 1998-2002

- Field Radio Operator; responsible for set up, maintenance, and operation of communications equipment in the field to establish and maintain secure communication with other units. Secret security clearance
- Squad leader; meritorious promotions and commendations

## **CORE SKILLS**

- IP network architecture, design, and operation
- Learning and teaching; able to quickly ramp up in new subject areas and then teach others
- Writing for technical and non-technical audiences; design documents, training, blogs, wikis, how-to's
- Cross-functional consensus building and collaborative problem solving
- Interviewing, coaching, mentoring, and growing distributed engineering organizations
- Standards development, architecture reviews, system design, and code reviews
- Technology evaluation and vendor management
- Internet peering and interconnection

## **TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE**

- Hardware and software including Juniper, Cisco, Arista, Dell, Cumulus, Quanta, PaloAlto, A10, F5, RaspberryPi
- OSPF, IS-IS, BGP/MP-BGP, Anycast, MPLS VPNs, RSVP-TE, VxLAN, PIM
- Public, private, and hybrid cloud infrastructure and connectivity; AWS, GCP, Azure, Linode
- Software development using Go, Python, Bash, Git, Make, Docker, SQL
- Installation and operation of Debian/Ubuntu, RHEL/CentOS, Fedora, FreeBSD, and VMWare ESXi servers
- Provisioning and configuration management with Terraform, Ansible, Puppet, Nornir, RANCID, Jinja, NETCONF
- IP address planning and management, DNS/DDI/DCIM using Bind, Infoblox, Device42, BBNA/TSNA

# **CERTIFICATIONS & AFFILIATIONS**

Member, NANOG	2012-Present
Board Member, Customer Advisory Board, DE-CIX	2014-2016
Vice President, Colorado Chapter of the Internet Society (COISOC)	2011-2016
Steering Committee Member, Rocky Mountain IPv6 Task Force (RMv6TF)	2011-2016
Juniper Networks Certified Internet Specialist (JNCIS-ENT)	2012-2015
Juniper Networks Certified Internet Specialist (JNCIS-M)	2006-2009
Cisco Certified Network Professional (CCNP)	2002-2008

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Associate of Arts, Physics**

Miami-Dade College